JUAN DAVID MORALES NAVARRETE

+57 312 3426116 - jmoralesn2@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juan-david-morales-navarrete/

https://github.com/jmoralesn2

Economist specialized in Data Analysis, and Data Science. Out-of-the-box thinking while coding and creating programs in Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn) and SQL (MySQL, and PostgreSQL) focused on data analysis and machine learning. Experience using Tableau to create dashboards and find insights to propose business solutions. Productive usage of economic theory and analytics to find strengths, weaknesses, and business opportunities to create tools that generate impact. Ability to communicate fluently in English and Spanish. Experience working well in diverse group settings, challenging environments, and goal-oriented communities.

English C1 - Excel - Tableau - Python - PostgreSQL - MySQL Creative Problem Solving - Teamwork - Leadership

Work Experience

Camper Services Coordinator – Sherman Lake YMCA Outdoor Center, Michigan, USA

05/2021 – 08/2021

01/2022 - 08/2022

- o Coach campers and staff to ensure a more inclusive environment at Summer Camp.
- o Communicate with parents to create plans and make experiences more valuable for campers.
- o Facilitate activities to raise mental health and diversity awareness with children and seasonal staff.
- Deal with any serious behavioral issues and report their development to the Summer Camp Director and Assistant Camp Director.

Junior Editor Assistant (Intern)- Revista CIFE Scientific Journal, Bogotá, Colombia

06/2020 - 07/2021

- Execute and control the flow of manuscripts.
- Permanent updating of the Journal's databases.
- Manage activities related to the participation of both national and international calls.
- o Development of a scientific article about Parity Purchase Power.
- o Indexate in Publindex from the Colombian Science Ministry

Education

Bachelor's degree in Economics – Universidad Santo Tomas

2022

Certifications

Business Analysis for Data Science – Platzi

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp – Udemy

2022